0,1,0,"If that is the case, after the child is born, the father will go to the mother's home, and present the family matriarch with gifts, asking to be accepted as the father.","[{'B_human': 'child'}, {'B_human': 'father'}, {'B_human': 'mat'}, {'B_human': 'father'}]",DiGraph with 26 nodes and 25 edges,and,that,:condition,,,,,,,
4,1,18,British investor,"[{'MISC': 'British'}, {'B_human': 'investor'}]",DiGraph with 6 nodes and 5 edges,person,country,:mod,,,,,,,
5,1,25,"According to government sources, the killing happened yesterday.",[],DiGraph with 6 nodes and 5 edges,source,government-organization,:mod,,,,,,,
6,1,44,A large number of people gathered.,[],DiGraph with 4 nodes and 3 edges,number,large,:mod,,,,,,,
7,1,46,20 Canadian dollars,[{'MISC': 'Canadian'}],DiGraph with 6 nodes and 5 edges,dollar,country,:mod,,,,,,,
8,1,58,10% of smokers die of lung cancer.,[{'B_human': 'smoke'}],DiGraph with 13 nodes and 12 edges,die-01,cause-01,:ARG1-of,,,,,,,
10,1,67,A team of researchers made a discovery .,[{'B_human': 'researchers'}],DiGraph with 4 nodes and 3 edges,team,person,:consist-of,,,,,,,
16,1,83,The mayor arrived with a police escort .,[{'B_human': 'mayor'}],DiGraph with 6 nodes and 5 edges,escort,police,:mod,,,,,,,
17,1,84,I ate pasta with tomato sauce .,[{'PER': 'I'}],DiGraph with 5 nodes and 4 edges,sauce,tomato,:mod,,,,,,,
21,1,95,"In the 1974 soccer World Cup final, Germany beat the Netherlands 2-1.","[{'MISC': 'World Cup'}, {'LOC': 'Germany'}, {'LOC': 'Netherlands'}]",DiGraph with 21 nodes and 20 edges,game,soccer,:mod,,,,,,,
22,1,108,A special gubernatorial election will take place next Tuesday .,[],DiGraph with 7 nodes and 6 edges,date-entity,next,:mod,,,,,,,
23,1,109,microbial virus,[],DiGraph with 2 nodes and 1 edges,virus,microbe,:mod,,,,,,,
24,1,111,Which team won ?,[],DiGraph with 3 nodes and 2 edges,amr-unknown,team,:mod,,,,,,,
25,1,112,this Wednesday afternoon,[],DiGraph with 4 nodes and 3 edges,date-entity,this,:mod,,,,,,,
29,1,116,The game will be canceled if it rains .,[],DiGraph with 3 nodes and 2 edges,cancel-01,rain-01,:condition,,,,,,,
30,1,117,"In the case of rain, the game will be canceled .",[],DiGraph with 3 nodes and 2 edges,cancel-01,rain-01,:condition,,,,,,,
31,1,118,The game will be canceled unless the rain stops .,[],DiGraph with 5 nodes and 4 edges,cancel-01,stop-01,:condition,,,,,,,
32,1,122,high tech companies like IBM and Google,"[{'ORG': 'IBM'}, {'ORG': 'Google'}]",DiGraph with 12 nodes and 11 edges,company,tech,:mod,,,,,,,
33,1,138,"I like classical music, but John likes jazz .","[{'PER': 'John'}, {'PER': 'I'}]",DiGraph with 11 nodes and 10 edges,music,classics,:mod,,,,,,,
34,1,150,Group A: (1) Germany (2) Brazil (3) Italy (4) Argentina,"[{'LOC': 'Germany'}, {'LOC': 'Brazil'}, {'LOC': 'Italy'}, {'LOC': 'Argentina'}]",DiGraph with 24 nodes and 23 edges,group,"""A""",:mod,,,,,,,
35,1,153,Never do that again.,[],DiGraph with 6 nodes and 5 edges,do-02,again,:mod,,,,,,,
41,1,174,He said he would support them as long as they didn't break any rules.,"[{'PER': 'He'}, {'PER': 'he'}, {'PER': 'them'}, {'PER': 'they'}]",DiGraph with 11 nodes and 10 edges,rule,any,:mod,,,,,,,
42,1,174,He said he would support them as long as they didn't break any rules.,"[{'PER': 'He'}, {'PER': 'he'}, {'PER': 'them'}, {'PER': 'they'}]",DiGraph with 11 nodes and 10 edges,support-01,as-long-as,:condition,,,,,,,
43,1,178,only 10 minutes,[],DiGraph with 3 nodes and 2 edges,temporal-quantity :quant 10,only,:mod,,,,,,,
44,1,179,The mayor proposed to lower crime by hiring more police officers.,"[{'B_human': 'mayor'}, {'B_human': 'officers'}]",DiGraph with 12 nodes and 11 edges,person,more,:mod,,,,,,,
45,1,188,There was a big explosion .,[],DiGraph with 2 nodes and 1 edges,explode-01,big,:mod,,,,,,,
46,1,190,Our next meeting will be on Friday at 11am .,[],DiGraph with 6 nodes and 5 edges,meet-01,next,:mod,,,,,,,
47,1,203,Three Roman legions were annihilated in the Battle of the Teutoburg Forest in 9 AD .,"[{'MISC': 'Roman'}, {'MISC': 'Battle of the'}, {'LOC': 'Teutoburg Forest'}]",DiGraph with 16 nodes and 15 edges,legion,country,:mod,,,,,,,
48,1,205,academic year 2011-2012,[],DiGraph with 4 nodes and 3 edges,year,academia,:mod,,,,,,,
49,1,206,United States government fiscal year 2012,[{'LOC': 'United States'}],DiGraph with 10 nodes and 9 edges,year,finance,:mod,,,,,,,
50,1,206,United States government fiscal year 2012,[{'LOC': 'United States'}],DiGraph with 10 nodes and 9 edges,year,government-organization,:mod,,,,,,,
51,1,229,What a great book!,[],DiGraph with 3 nodes and 2 edges,book,great,:mod,,,,,,,
52,1,233,"Dad, I need more money.","[{'B_human': 'Dad'}, {'PER': 'I'}]",DiGraph with 10 nodes and 9 edges,money,more,:mod,,,,,,,
53,1,237,Most students don't like math.,[{'B_human': 'students'}],DiGraph with 5 nodes and 4 edges,person,most,:mod,,,,,,,
54,1,263,nuclear weapons,[],DiGraph with 2 nodes and 1 edges,weapon,nucleus,:mod,,,,,,,
55,1,264,The big fish wants to eat the little fish.,"[{'B_animal': 'fish'}, {'B_animal': 'fish'}]",DiGraph with 7 nodes and 6 edges,fish,big,:mod,,,,,,,
56,1,264,The big fish wants to eat the little fish.,"[{'B_animal': 'fish'}, {'B_animal': 'fish'}]",DiGraph with 7 nodes and 6 edges,fish,little,:mod,,,,,,,
57,1,269,United Nations Secretary General Ban Ki-moon traveled to Egypt.,"[{'ORG': 'United Nations'}, {'PER': 'Ban Ki-moon'}, {'LOC': 'Egypt'}]",DiGraph with 18 nodes and 17 edges,secretary,general,:mod,,,,,,,
58,1,275,Should we increase security at the expense of democratic principles?,[{'PER': 'we'}],DiGraph with 8 nodes and 7 edges,principle,democracy,:mod,,,,,,,
59,1,284,"She works for UBS, a big Swiss bank.","[{'ORG': 'UBS'}, {'MISC': 'Swiss'}, {'PER': 'She'}]",DiGraph with 11 nodes and 10 edges,bank,big,:mod,,,,,,,
60,1,284,"She works for UBS, a big Swiss bank.","[{'ORG': 'UBS'}, {'MISC': 'Swiss'}, {'PER': 'She'}]",DiGraph with 11 nodes and 10 edges,bank,country,:mod,,,,,,,
61,1,294,"When I met her for the first time, Mary still worked for Goldman Sachs.","[{'PER': 'Mary'}, {'ORG': 'Goldman Sachs'}, {'PER': 'I'}, {'PER': 'her'}]",DiGraph with 16 nodes and 15 edges,work-01,still,:mod,,,,,,,
62,1,297,North Korea agreed to dismantle the nuclear reactor in return for economic aid.,[{'LOC': 'North Korea'}],DiGraph with 15 nodes and 14 edges,reactor,nucleus,:mod,,,,,,,
63,1,298,"The company paid $20,000 in return for the release of all claims.",[],DiGraph with 9 nodes and 8 edges,claim-02,all,:mod,,,,,,,
64,1,300,Lawmakers demanded the ban of chemical weapons.,[{'B_human': 'Law'}],DiGraph with 6 nodes and 5 edges,weapon,chemical,:mod,,,,,,,
65,1,304,audio and/or video components,[],DiGraph with 4 nodes and 3 edges,component,and-or,:mod,,,,,,,
66,1,305,"During negotiations between North Korea and the US, North Korean officials promised that the country will freeze its nuclear program.","[{'LOC': 'North Korea'}, {'LOC': 'US'}, {'MISC': 'North Korean'}, {'B_human': 'officials'}, {'PER': 'US'}]",DiGraph with 20 nodes and 19 edges,program,nucleus,:mod,,,,,,,
67,1,306,"During negotiations between North Korea and the US, North Korean officials promised that North Korea will freeze its nuclear program.","[{'LOC': 'North Korea'}, {'LOC': 'US'}, {'MISC': 'North Korean'}, {'LOC': 'North Korea'}, {'B_human': 'officials'}, {'PER': 'US'}]",DiGraph with 20 nodes and 19 edges,program,nucleus,:mod,,,,,,,
68,1,307,North Korean officials promised that North Korea will soon begin to freeze its nuclear program.,"[{'MISC': 'North Korean'}, {'LOC': 'North Korea'}, {'B_human': 'officials'}]",DiGraph with 17 nodes and 16 edges,program,nucleus,:mod,,,,,,,
70,1,325,USC Associate Professor for Mathematics Jay Bartroff,"[{'ORG': 'USC'}, {'PER': 'Jay Bartro'}, {'B_human': 'Associate Professor'}]",DiGraph with 12 nodes and 11 edges,professor,associate,:mod,,,,,,,
71,1,333,We met only once.,[{'PER': 'We'}],DiGraph with 5 nodes and 4 edges,have-frequency-91,only,:mod,,,,,,,
72,1,348,China spent 430 billion yuan RMB on water conservation.,"[{'LOC': 'China'}, {'MISC': 'R'}]",DiGraph with 11 nodes and 10 edges,yuan,renminbi,:mod,,,,,,,
73,1,349,Buffalo buffalo Buffalo buffalo buffalo buffalo Buffalo buffalo.,"[{'MISC': 'Buffalo'}, {'MISC': 'Buffalo'}, {'MISC': 'Buffalo'}, {'B_animal': 'Buffalo buffalo Buffalo buffalo buffalo buffalo Buffalo buffalo'}]",DiGraph with 11 nodes and 10 edges,buffalo,city,:source,,,,,,,
74,1,349,Buffalo buffalo Buffalo buffalo buffalo buffalo Buffalo buffalo.,"[{'MISC': 'Buffalo'}, {'MISC': 'Buffalo'}, {'MISC': 'Buffalo'}, {'B_animal': 'Buffalo buffalo Buffalo buffalo buffalo buffalo Buffalo buffalo'}]",DiGraph with 11 nodes and 10 edges,buffalo,c,:source,,,,,,,
75,1,349,Buffalo buffalo Buffalo buffalo buffalo buffalo Buffalo buffalo.,"[{'MISC': 'Buffalo'}, {'MISC': 'Buffalo'}, {'MISC': 'Buffalo'}, {'B_animal': 'Buffalo buffalo Buffalo buffalo buffalo buffalo Buffalo buffalo'}]",DiGraph with 11 nodes and 10 edges,buffalo,c,:source,,,,,,,
76,1,351,He works for the news agency AFP.,"[{'ORG': 'AFP'}, {'PER': 'He'}]",DiGraph with 7 nodes and 6 edges,agency,news,:mod,,,,,,,
77,1,375,Of course I know.,[{'PER': 'I'}],DiGraph with 3 nodes and 2 edges,know-01,of-course,:mod,,,,,,,
78,1,376,deputy minister of defense,[{'B_human': 'minister'}],DiGraph with 3 nodes and 2 edges,minister,deputy,:mod,,,,,,,
79,1,377,David Cameron is the prime minister of the United Kingdom.,"[{'PER': 'David Cameron'}, {'LOC': 'United Kingdom'}, {'B_human': 'minister'}]",DiGraph with 13 nodes and 12 edges,minister,prime,:mod,,,,,,,
80,1,379,a state-of-the-art missile defense system,[],DiGraph with 4 nodes and 3 edges,system,state-of-the-art,:mod,,,,,,,
81,1,381,Leukemia is a kind of cancer.,[{'MISC': 'Le'}],DiGraph with 8 nodes and 7 edges,disease,kind,:mod,,,,,,,
82,1,382,Leukemia is a type of cancer.,[{'MISC': 'Le'}],DiGraph with 8 nodes and 7 edges,disease,type,:mod,,,,,,,
83,1,383,Leukemia is a form of cancer.,[{'MISC': 'Le'}],DiGraph with 8 nodes and 7 edges,disease,form,:mod,,,,,,,
84,1,384,Leukemia is some sort of cancer.,[{'MISC': 'Le'}],DiGraph with 8 nodes and 7 edges,disease,sort,:mod,,,,,,,
86,1,407,The package was delivered on time.,[],DiGraph with 3 nodes and 2 edges,deliver-01,on-time,:mod,,,,,,,
89,1,411,Why did the chicken cross the road?,[],DiGraph with 5 nodes and 4 edges,cross-02,cause-01,:ARG1-of,,,,,,,
90,1,413,The number of cancer deaths has been increasing.,[],DiGraph with 9 nodes and 8 edges,die-01,cause-01,:ARG1-of,,,,,,,
91,1,415,He left last week.,[{'PER': 'He'}],DiGraph with 4 nodes and 3 edges,week,last,:mod,,,,,,,
92,1,417,"By and large, that information is accurate.",[],DiGraph with 4 nodes and 3 edges,information,that,:mod,,,,,,,
93,1,419,The Soviet era ended in 1991.,[{'MISC': 'Soviet'}],DiGraph with 9 nodes and 8 edges,era,country,:mod,,,,,,,
95,1,425,those boys,[{'B_human': 'boys'}],DiGraph with 2 nodes and 1 edges,boy,that,:mod,,,,,,,
96,1,430,All the boys left.,[{'B_human': 'boys'}],DiGraph with 3 nodes and 2 edges,boy,all,:mod,,,,,,,
97,1,433,the big and heavy ball,[],DiGraph with 3 nodes and 2 edges,ball,big,:mod,,,,,,,
98,1,433,the big and heavy ball,[],DiGraph with 3 nodes and 2 edges,ball,heavy,:mod,,,,,,,
99,1,444,He overslept again.,[{'PER': 'He'}],DiGraph with 3 nodes and 2 edges,oversleep-01,again,:mod,,,,,,,
100,1,446,countries with huge deficits,[],DiGraph with 4 nodes and 3 edges,deficit,huge,:mod,,,,,,,
101,1,450,government figures,[],DiGraph with 3 nodes and 2 edges,figure,government-organization,:source,,,,,,,
104,1,475,my good old friend Michael,"[{'PER': 'Michael'}, {'B_human': 'friend'}]",DiGraph with 8 nodes and 7 edges,have-rel-role-91,old,:mod,,,,,,,
105,1,477,Berlin is a sister city of Los Angeles.,"[{'LOC': 'Berlin'}, {'LOC': 'Los Angeles'}]",DiGraph with 12 nodes and 11 edges,city,sister,:mod,,,,,,,
106,1,478,Berlin and Los Angeles are sister cities.,"[{'LOC': 'Berlin'}, {'LOC': 'Los Angeles'}]",DiGraph with 14 nodes and 13 edges,city,sister,:mod,,,,,,,
107,1,478,Berlin and Los Angeles are sister cities.,"[{'LOC': 'Berlin'}, {'LOC': 'Los Angeles'}]",DiGraph with 14 nodes and 13 edges,city,sister,:mod,,,,,,,
108,1,491,"After all, he is still my brother.","[{'B_human': 'brother'}, {'PER': 'he'}]",DiGraph with 6 nodes and 5 edges,have-rel-role-91,still,:mod,,,,,,,
109,1,492,after all these years,[],DiGraph with 4 nodes and 3 edges,year,this,:mod,,,,,,,
110,1,492,after all these years,[],DiGraph with 4 nodes and 3 edges,year,all,:mod,,,,,,,
112,1,502,John still loves his ex.,"[{'PER': 'John'}, {'B_human': 'ex'}]",DiGraph with 11 nodes and 10 edges,love-01,still,:mod,,,,,,,
114,1,514,the poet Dr. Seuss,"[{'PER': 'Seuss'}, {'B_human': 'poet'}]",DiGraph with 4 nodes and 3 edges,doctor,poet,:mod,,,,,,,
115,1,518,He sold the company last October.,[{'PER': 'He'}],DiGraph with 6 nodes and 5 edges,date-entity,last,:mod,,,,,,,
116,1,522,I passed the exam this past year.,[{'PER': 'I'}],DiGraph with 5 nodes and 4 edges,year,past,:mod,,,,,,,
117,1,523,He called this past Tuesday.,[{'PER': 'He'}],DiGraph with 5 nodes and 4 edges,date-entity,past,:mod,,,,,,,
118,1,531,"If this happens again, I will resign.",[{'PER': 'I'}],DiGraph with 5 nodes and 4 edges,event,this,:mod,,,,,,,
119,1,531,"If this happens again, I will resign.",[{'PER': 'I'}],DiGraph with 5 nodes and 4 edges,event,again,:mod,,,,,,,
120,1,531,"If this happens again, I will resign.",[{'PER': 'I'}],DiGraph with 5 nodes and 4 edges,resign-01,event,:condition,,,,,,,
121,1,532,Something weird took place in the park.,[],DiGraph with 3 nodes and 2 edges,event,weird,:mod,,,,,,,
122,1,533,What happened in Japan?,[{'LOC': 'Japan'}],DiGraph with 6 nodes and 5 edges,event,amr-unknown,:mod,,,,,,,
123,1,534,"Instead, they found an old coin.",[{'PER': 'they'}],DiGraph with 5 nodes and 4 edges,coin,old,:mod,,,,,,,
124,1,535,She was a little bit nervous.,[{'PER': 'She'}],DiGraph with 4 nodes and 3 edges,bit,little,:mod,,,,,,,
125,1,543,Hot!!! :P,[],DiGraph with 4 nodes and 3 edges,hot-03,emoticon,:mod,,,,,,,
126,1,545,a 5.6% interest rate,[],DiGraph with 4 nodes and 3 edges,rate,interest,:mod,,,,,,,
129,1,553,"If I remember correctly, he lost.","[{'PER': 'I'}, {'PER': 'he'}]",DiGraph with 6 nodes and 5 edges,lose-03,remember-01,:condition,,,,,,,
130,1,562,That's a really big fish.,[{'B_animal': 'fish'}],DiGraph with 4 nodes and 3 edges,fish,big,:mod,,,,,,,
131,1,563,The earthquake occurred in Indonesia's remote eastern province of Papua.,"[{'LOC': 'Indonesia'}, {'LOC': 'Papua'}]",DiGraph with 12 nodes and 11 edges,east,remote,:mod,,,,,,,
132,1,567,"It rained, so we postponed the game.",[{'PER': 'we'}],DiGraph with 5 nodes and 4 edges,rain-01,cause-01,:ARG0-of,,,,,,,
133,1,570,I'm sick too.,[],DiGraph with 3 nodes and 2 edges,sick-05,too,:mod,,,,,,,
134,1,576,He found something else.,[{'PER': 'He'}],DiGraph with 4 nodes and 3 edges,something,else,:mod,,,,,,,
135,1,577,Everybody else had already left.,[],DiGraph with 4 nodes and 3 edges,everybody,else,:mod,,,,,,,
136,1,578,We insist that you adhere to the contract or else we will sue you.,"[{'PER': 'We'}, {'PER': 'you'}, {'PER': 'we'}, {'PER': 'you'}]",DiGraph with 12 nodes and 11 edges,sue-02,have-polarity-91,:condition,,,,,,,
137,1,579,"There was another fire alarm, but I had to leave anyway.",[{'PER': 'I'}],DiGraph with 7 nodes and 6 edges,obligate-01,anyway,:mod,,,,,,,
139,1,582,Call 911 if he comes back anyway.,[{'PER': 'he'}],DiGraph with 7 nodes and 6 edges,call-02,return-01,:condition,,,,,,,
140,1,594,Jimbo's football team,"[{'PER': 'Jim'}, {'PER': 'bo'}]",DiGraph with 6 nodes and 5 edges,team,football,:mod,,,,,,,
141,1,599,"As shown in Table 5, accuracy improves with the amount of training data.",[],DiGraph with 8 nodes and 7 edges,table,5,:mod,,,,,,,
142,1,600,We treated CHO-K1 cells with HRG ligand to induce maximal ERBB3 phosphorylation (Fig. 6a).,"[{'MISC': 'CH'}, {'MISC': 'ERBB'}, {'PER': 'We'}]",DiGraph with 22 nodes and 21 edges,figure,"""6a""",:mod,,,,,,,
143,1,602,"The protein can then be deacetylated. (Tsai et al., 2002)","[{'PER': 'T'}, {'PER': 'sai'}]",DiGraph with 15 nodes and 14 edges,person,other,:mod,,,,,,,
144,1,609,Police seized 50 pounds of heroin as well as two machine guns.,[],DiGraph with 10 nodes and 9 edges,gun,machine,:mod,,,,,,,
145,1,611,The first snowfall came as early as November 10.,[],DiGraph with 8 nodes and 7 edges,date-entity,early,:mod,,,,,,,
146,1,614,"As far as the CEO is concerned, he is the best at everything.","[{'B_human': 'CEO'}, {'PER': 'he'}]",DiGraph with 10 nodes and 9 edges,officer,chief,:mod,,,,,,,
147,1,614,"As far as the CEO is concerned, he is the best at everything.","[{'B_human': 'CEO'}, {'PER': 'he'}]",DiGraph with 10 nodes and 9 edges,officer,executive,:mod,,,,,,,
148,1,619,"The bicycle cost as much as $5,000.",[],DiGraph with 6 nodes and 5 edges,monetary-quantity,much,:mod,,,,,,,
149,1,624,Jerry visited all countries except Cuba.,"[{'PER': 'Jerry'}, {'LOC': 'Cuba'}]",DiGraph with 12 nodes and 11 edges,country,all,:mod,,,,,,,
150,1,625,I solved the math problem on my own.,[{'PER': 'I'}],DiGraph with 5 nodes and 4 edges,solve-01,by-oneself,:mod,,,,,,,
151,1,626,I solved the software problem by myself.,[{'PER': 'I'}],DiGraph with 5 nodes and 4 edges,solve-01,by-oneself,:mod,,,,,,,
152,1,628,All buildings within a mile of the explosion were damaged.,[],DiGraph with 9 nodes and 8 edges,building,all,:mod,,,,,,,
153,1,635,The energy will be supplied through wind turbines.,[],DiGraph with 4 nodes and 3 edges,turbine,wind,:mod,,,,,,,
154,1,640,This book is less expensive.,[],DiGraph with 5 nodes and 4 edges,book,this,:mod,,,,,,,
155,1,646,"When she arrived, he was still asleep.","[{'PER': 'she'}, {'PER': 'he'}]",DiGraph with 5 nodes and 4 edges,sleep-01,still,:mod,,,,,,,
156,1,647,"When all else fails, I use superglue.",[{'PER': 'I'}],DiGraph with 6 nodes and 5 edges,all,else,:mod,,,,,,,
157,1,647,"When all else fails, I use superglue.",[{'PER': 'I'}],DiGraph with 6 nodes and 5 edges,use-01,fail-01,:condition,,,,,,,
158,1,650,The drug has serious side effects.,[],DiGraph with 5 nodes and 4 edges,event,side,:mod,,,,,,,
159,1,652,Solutions with a pH less than 7 are said to be acidic.,[],DiGraph with 7 nodes and 6 edges,solution,less-than,:mod,,,,,,,
160,1,657,"The Japanese town bombed in 1945 was recently hit by deadly waves, causing devastating destruction.",[{'MISC': 'Japanese'}],DiGraph with 15 nodes and 14 edges,hit-01,cause-01,:ARG0-of,,,,,,,
161,1,664,"A 7.8 earthquake struck eastern Iran, killing 40 people in the village of Hiduj, severely damaging many of its buildings, and triggering an international aid response.","[{'LOC': 'Iran'}, {'LOC': 'Hiduj'}]",DiGraph with 26 nodes and 25 edges,respond-01,international,:mod,,,,,,,
162,1,676,I oppose weapons intended for killing other humans.,"[{'B_animal': 'humans'}, {'PER': 'I'}]",DiGraph with 7 nodes and 6 edges,human,other,:mod,,,,,,,
164,1,688,Biking to work kills two birds with one stone: it saves money and will help to lose weight.,[{'B_animal': 'birds'}],DiGraph with 11 nodes and 10 edges,bike-01,work-01,:destination,,,,,,,
166,1,696,former U.S. Deputy Secretary of Defense Paul Wolfowitz,"[{'LOC': 'U.S.'}, {'ORG': 'Defense'}, {'PER': 'Paul Wolfowitz'}, {'PER': 'US'}]",DiGraph with 13 nodes and 12 edges,secretary,deputy,:mod,,,,,,,
167,1,697,a big car,[],DiGraph with 2 nodes and 1 edges,car,big,:mod,,,,,,,
168,1,698,"John Smith, 30, blond, blue eyes, 6'2, 200 lbs.",[{'PER': 'John Smith'}],DiGraph with 22 nodes and 21 edges,person,blonde,:mod,,,,,,,
169,1,698,"John Smith, 30, blond, blue eyes, 6'2, 200 lbs.",[{'PER': 'John Smith'}],DiGraph with 22 nodes and 21 edges,person,tall,:mod,,,,,,,
170,1,698,"John Smith, 30, blond, blue eyes, 6'2, 200 lbs.",[{'PER': 'John Smith'}],DiGraph with 22 nodes and 21 edges,eye,blue,:mod,,,,,,,
171,1,698,"John Smith, 30, blond, blue eyes, 6'2, 200 lbs.",[{'PER': 'John Smith'}],DiGraph with 22 nodes and 21 edges,person,eye,:part,,,,,,,
172,1,701,USC CS Assistant Professor Wyatt LLoyd,"[{'ORG': 'USC CS'}, {'PER': 'Wyatt LL'}]",DiGraph with 13 nodes and 12 edges,professor,assistant,:mod,,,,,,,
173,1,701,USC CS Assistant Professor Wyatt LLoyd,"[{'ORG': 'USC CS'}, {'PER': 'Wyatt LL'}]",DiGraph with 13 nodes and 12 edges,science,computer,:mod,,,,,,,
174,1,708,the wise girl,[{'B_human': 'girl'}],DiGraph with 2 nodes and 1 edges,girl,wise,:mod,,,,,,,
175,1,710,"DNA, or deoxyribonucleic acid, is the hereditary material in humans and almost all other organisms.",[],DiGraph with 13 nodes and 12 edges,material,hereditary,:mod,,,,,,,
176,1,710,"DNA, or deoxyribonucleic acid, is the hereditary material in humans and almost all other organisms.",[],DiGraph with 13 nodes and 12 edges,organism,other,:mod,,,,,,,
177,1,710,"DNA, or deoxyribonucleic acid, is the hereditary material in humans and almost all other organisms.",[],DiGraph with 13 nodes and 12 edges,organism,all,:mod,,,,,,,
178,1,710,"DNA, or deoxyribonucleic acid, is the hereditary material in humans and almost all other organisms.",[],DiGraph with 13 nodes and 12 edges,all,almost,:mod,,,,,,,
179,1,716,The French government raised taxes on luxury goods.,[{'MISC': 'French'}],DiGraph with 11 nodes and 10 edges,good,luxury,:mod,,,,,,,
180,1,717,The dermatologist examined the patient for symptoms skin cancer.,"[{'B_human': 'der'}, {'B_human': 'patient'}]",DiGraph with 9 nodes and 8 edges,symptom,disease,:mod,,,,,,,
181,1,718,TDAG51 up-regulation was attenuated by MEK inhibition (Figure 5).,"[{'MISC': 'TD'}, {'MISC': 'MEK'}]",DiGraph with 14 nodes and 13 edges,figure,5,:mod,,,,,,,
182,1,720,"The last time I saw her, she was still a child.","[{'B_human': 'child'}, {'PER': 'I'}, {'PER': 'her'}, {'PER': 'she'}]",DiGraph with 7 nodes and 6 edges,child,still,:mod,,,,,,,
183,1,720,"The last time I saw her, she was still a child.","[{'B_human': 'child'}, {'PER': 'I'}, {'PER': 'her'}, {'PER': 'she'}]",DiGraph with 7 nodes and 6 edges,see-01,last,:mod,,,,,,,
184,1,721,The CEO of Oshkosh Corp. talked about IEDs on TV.,"[{'ORG': 'Oshkosh Corp'}, {'ORG': 'I'}, {'MISC': 'ED'}, {'B_human': 'CEO'}]",DiGraph with 16 nodes and 15 edges,officer,chief,:mod,,,,,,,
185,1,721,The CEO of Oshkosh Corp. talked about IEDs on TV.,"[{'ORG': 'Oshkosh Corp'}, {'ORG': 'I'}, {'MISC': 'ED'}, {'B_human': 'CEO'}]",DiGraph with 16 nodes and 15 edges,officer,executive,:mod,,,,,,,
186,1,722,Superbowl ad rates increased again.,[],DiGraph with 8 nodes and 7 edges,increase-01,again,:mod,,,,,,,
187,1,722,Superbowl ad rates increased again.,[],DiGraph with 8 nodes and 7 edges,rate,advertise-01,:mod,,,,,,,
188,1,726,12 fl.oz. of misc. bevs,[],DiGraph with 6 nodes and 5 edges,beverage,miscellaneous,:mod,,,,,,,
189,1,726,12 fl.oz. of misc. bevs,[],DiGraph with 6 nodes and 5 edges,fluid-ounce,fluid,:mod,,,,,,,
190,1,732,a waltz in A-flat major,[],DiGraph with 6 nodes and 5 edges,waltz,music-key,:mod,,,,,,,
191,1,733,Mahler's Symphony No. 6 in A minor,"[{'PER': 'Mahler'}, {'MISC': 'Symphony No. 6'}]",DiGraph with 12 nodes and 11 edges,symphony,6,:mod,,,,,,,
192,1,733,Mahler's Symphony No. 6 in A minor,"[{'PER': 'Mahler'}, {'MISC': 'Symphony No. 6'}]",DiGraph with 12 nodes and 11 edges,symphony,music-key,:mod,,,,,,,
195,1,735,DH needed treatment at A&E after the attack.,"[{'ORG': 'DH'}, {'ORG': 'A&E'}]",DiGraph with 15 nodes and 14 edges,person,dear,:mod,,,,,,,
196,1,736,"The adulteress was required to wear a scarlet ""A"" on her dress.","[{'B_human': 'adult'}, {'PER': 'her'}]",DiGraph with 10 nodes and 9 edges,string-entity,scarlet,:mod,,,,,,,
197,1,740,"In English, ""a"" is a very common word.",[{'MISC': 'English'}],DiGraph with 9 nodes and 8 edges,word,common,:mod,,,,,,,
198,1,743,"""−"" means mock treatment.",[],DiGraph with 5 nodes and 4 edges,treat-04,mock,:mod,,,,,,,
199,1,749,The mayor didn't truly understand his citizens' concerns.,"[{'B_human': 'mayor'}, {'B_human': 'citizens'}]",DiGraph with 9 nodes and 8 edges,citizen,c3,:mod,,,,,,,
201,1,756,What the hell did you tell her?,"[{'PER': 'you'}, {'PER': 'her'}]",DiGraph with 6 nodes and 5 edges,tell-01,hell,:mod,,,,,,,
202,1,760,"All employees will be treated equally without regard to race, gender, national origin, color, ethnicity, religion, disability or sexual orientation.",[{'B_human': 'employees'}],DiGraph with 17 nodes and 16 edges,person,all,:mod,,,,,,,
203,1,762,"For more information, click <a href=""http://www.hollywoodbowl.com"">here</a>.",[],DiGraph with 9 nodes and 8 edges,information,more,:mod,,,,,,,
204,1,771,"<a href=""http://gutenberg.net.au/ebooks03/0300771h.html"">The Little Prince</a>",[{'MISC': 'Little Prince'}],DiGraph with 5 nodes and 4 edges,prince,little,:mod,,,,,,,
205,1,773,"Raf-1 also correlated with nuclear activated MAPK (p=0.0022, r<sup>2</sup>=0.1525).","[{'MISC': 'Raf'}, {'MISC': '1'}, {'MISC': 'MA'}]",DiGraph with 15 nodes and 14 edges,correlate-01,nucleus,:mod,,,,,,,
206,1,773,"Raf-1 also correlated with nuclear activated MAPK (p=0.0022, r<sup>2</sup>=0.1525).","[{'MISC': 'Raf'}, {'MISC': '1'}, {'MISC': 'MA'}]",DiGraph with 15 nodes and 14 edges,correlate-01,also,:mod,,,,,,,
207,1,774,"All of these predictions were confirmed experimentally (Fig. 4, A-C).",[],DiGraph with 14 nodes and 13 edges,thing,all,:mod,,,,,,,
208,1,774,"All of these predictions were confirmed experimentally (Fig. 4, A-C).",[],DiGraph with 14 nodes and 13 edges,thing,this,:mod,,,,,,,
209,1,774,"All of these predictions were confirmed experimentally (Fig. 4, A-C).",[],DiGraph with 14 nodes and 13 edges,figure,"""4A""",:mod,,,,,,,
210,1,774,"All of these predictions were confirmed experimentally (Fig. 4, A-C).",[],DiGraph with 14 nodes and 13 edges,figure,"""4B""",:mod,,,,,,,
211,1,774,"All of these predictions were confirmed experimentally (Fig. 4, A-C).",[],DiGraph with 14 nodes and 13 edges,figure,"""4C""",:mod,,,,,,,
212,1,775,These frequencies were significantly different by Chi square test (p value = 0.001).,[{'MISC': 'Chi'}],DiGraph with 12 nodes and 11 edges,have-frequency-91,this,:mod,,,,,,,
213,1,780,Occupy Wall Street protesters demanded a reduction in economic inequality.,"[{'LOC': 'Wall Street'}, {'B_human': 'protesters'}]",DiGraph with 13 nodes and 12 edges,person,political-movement,:mod,,,,,,,
214,1,780,Occupy Wall Street protesters demanded a reduction in economic inequality.,"[{'LOC': 'Wall Street'}, {'B_human': 'protesters'}]",DiGraph with 13 nodes and 12 edges,equal-01,economy,:mod,,,,,,,
215,1,781,Vietnam is a communist nation.,[{'LOC': 'Vietnam'}],DiGraph with 9 nodes and 8 edges,nation,political-movement,:mod,,,,,,,
216,1,782,The mayor condemned the neo-Nazi violence.,"[{'MISC': 'neo'}, {'MISC': 'Nazi'}, {'B_human': 'mayor'}]",DiGraph with 8 nodes and 7 edges,violence,person,:mod,,,,,,,
217,1,782,The mayor condemned the neo-Nazi violence.,"[{'MISC': 'neo'}, {'MISC': 'Nazi'}, {'B_human': 'mayor'}]",DiGraph with 8 nodes and 7 edges,person,political-movement,:mod,,,,,,,
218,1,788,Where the bloody fuck did you hide my beer?,[{'PER': 'you'}],DiGraph with 9 nodes and 8 edges,hide-01,fuck,:mod,,,,,,,
219,1,788,Where the bloody fuck did you hide my beer?,[{'PER': 'you'}],DiGraph with 9 nodes and 8 edges,fuck,bloody,:mod,,,,,,,
220,1,789,Give me the fucking beer!,[{'PER': 'me'}],DiGraph with 6 nodes and 5 edges,beer,fucking :mode expressive,:mod,,,,,,,
221,1,790,WTF are you talking about?,[{'PER': 'you'}],DiGraph with 5 nodes and 4 edges,talk-01,fuck,:mod,,,,,,,
222,1,799,I know why the chicken crossed the road.,[{'PER': 'I'}],DiGraph with 7 nodes and 6 edges,thing,cause-01,:ARG0-of,,,,,,,
223,1,807,This food will last us for at least three months.,[{'PER': 'us'}],DiGraph with 8 nodes and 7 edges,food,this,:mod,,,,,,,
224,1,808,BP estimates that global oil reserves will last 53.3 years at the current production rates.,[{'ORG': 'BP'}],DiGraph with 16 nodes and 15 edges,reserve,oil,:mod,,,,,,,
225,1,808,BP estimates that global oil reserves will last 53.3 years at the current production rates.,[{'ORG': 'BP'}],DiGraph with 16 nodes and 15 edges,reserve,globe,:mod,,,,,,,
226,1,808,BP estimates that global oil reserves will last 53.3 years at the current production rates.,[{'ORG': 'BP'}],DiGraph with 16 nodes and 15 edges,rate,produce-01,:mod,,,,,,,
227,1,809,This well-built car will last you for a very long time.,[{'PER': 'you'}],DiGraph with 9 nodes and 8 edges,car,this,:mod,,,,,,,
228,1,817,Gefitinib binds wild-type EGFR kinase with K<sub>d</sub> = 53.5 nM.,"[{'ORG': 'Gefitinib'}, {'MISC': 'E'}]",DiGraph with 15 nodes and 14 edges,kinase,wild-type,:mod,,,,,,,
229,1,825,Seats in rows 6-20 cost $30.,[],DiGraph with 9 nodes and 8 edges,row,value-interval,:mod,,,,,,,
230,1,826,"To prepare for tomorrow's class, please read pages 320-325.",[],DiGraph with 12 nodes and 11 edges,page,value-interval,:mod,,,,,,,
231,1,836,"The most common word in English is ""the"".",[{'MISC': 'English'}],DiGraph with 10 nodes and 9 edges,word,language,:mod,,,,,,,
232,1,846,My name is Bill if you need me.,"[{'PER': 'Bill'}, {'PER': 'you'}, {'PER': 'me'}]",DiGraph with 11 nodes and 10 edges,relevant-01,need-01,:condition,,,,,,,
233,1,847,There is food in the fridge in case you get hungry.,[{'PER': 'you'}],DiGraph with 9 nodes and 8 edges,relevant-01,get-03,:condition,,,,,,,
234,1,853,Cuts are more or less unavoidable.,[],DiGraph with 4 nodes and 3 edges,possible-01 :polarity -,more-or-less,:mod,,,,,,,
235,1,855,Or you just tell them the truth.,"[{'PER': 'you'}, {'PER': 'them'}]",DiGraph with 6 nodes and 5 edges,tell-01,just,:mod,,,,,,,
236,1,857,This computer is small enough to fit in your pocket.,[],DiGraph with 9 nodes and 8 edges,computer,this,:mod,,,,,,,
237,1,859,I had scarcely enough drinking water to last a week.,[{'PER': 'I'}],DiGraph with 14 nodes and 13 edges,enough,scarce,:mod,,,,,,,
238,1,873,I need more light.,[{'PER': 'I'}],DiGraph with 4 nodes and 3 edges,light,more,:mod,,,,,,,
239,1,876,She married a man whom she had met only a month earlier.,"[{'B_human': 'man'}, {'PER': 'She'}, {'PER': 'she'}]",DiGraph with 11 nodes and 10 edges,temporal-quantity,only,:mod,,,,,,,
240,1,877,Inflation decreased to 1% in the latest quarter.,[],DiGraph with 6 nodes and 5 edges,quarter,last,:mod,,,,,,,
241,1,884,The vaccine shortage is an additional problem.,[],DiGraph with 4 nodes and 3 edges,problem,additional,:mod,,,,,,,
243,1,886,The cool and wet spring led to fewer wildfires.,[],DiGraph with 6 nodes and 5 edges,spring,wet,:mod,,,,,,,
244,1,886,The cool and wet spring led to fewer wildfires.,[],DiGraph with 6 nodes and 5 edges,wildfire,less,:mod,,,,,,,
247,1,895,The girl is almost as tall as the boy.,"[{'B_human': 'girl'}, {'B_human': 'boy'}]",DiGraph with 6 nodes and 5 edges,have-degree-91,almost,:mod,,,,,,,
248,1,899,This puppy is too cute.,[{'B_animal': 'puppy'}],DiGraph with 4 nodes and 3 edges,puppy,this,:mod,,,,,,,
249,1,900,"Johnny Ace's last words were ""It's okay! Gun's not loaded... see?""",[{'PER': 'Johnny Ace'}],DiGraph with 16 nodes and 15 edges,word,last,:mod,,,,,,,
250,1,905,St. Augustine was the earliest Spanish settlement in North America.,"[{'LOC': 'St. Augustine'}, {'MISC': 'Spanish'}, {'LOC': 'North America'}]",DiGraph with 19 nodes and 18 edges,settlement,country,:mod,,,,,,,
251,1,907,Have you read RAND's latest report on U.S. ground interventions?,"[{'ORG': 'RAND'}, {'LOC': 'U.S.'}, {'PER': 'you'}, {'PER': 'US'}]",DiGraph with 16 nodes and 15 edges,publication,last,:mod,,,,,,,
252,1,907,Have you read RAND's latest report on U.S. ground interventions?,"[{'ORG': 'RAND'}, {'LOC': 'U.S.'}, {'PER': 'you'}, {'PER': 'US'}]",DiGraph with 16 nodes and 15 edges,intervene-01,ground,:mod,,,,,,,
253,1,910,I might visit them again later next year.,"[{'PER': 'I'}, {'PER': 'them'}]",DiGraph with 9 nodes and 8 edges,visit-01,again,:mod,,,,,,,
254,1,910,I might visit them again later next year.,"[{'PER': 'I'}, {'PER': 'them'}]",DiGraph with 9 nodes and 8 edges,year,next,:mod,,,,,,,
255,1,914,He is a so called moocher.,"[{'B_human': 'm'}, {'PER': 'He'}]",DiGraph with 4 nodes and 3 edges,person,so-called,:mod,,,,,,,
256,1,922,The number of accidents decreased by more than 15% compared to last year.,[],DiGraph with 9 nodes and 8 edges,year,last,:mod,,,,,,,
257,1,925,House prices have risen to the point where an entire generation is struggling to afford a home.,[],DiGraph with 12 nodes and 11 edges,generation,entire,:mod,,,,,,,
258,1,929,"If the sun shines, we'll go to the beach; otherwise we will stay at home.",[{'PER': 'we'}],DiGraph with 12 nodes and 11 edges,go-02,shine-01,:condition,,,,,,,
259,1,929,"If the sun shines, we'll go to the beach; otherwise we will stay at home.",[{'PER': 'we'}],DiGraph with 12 nodes and 11 edges,stay-01,have-polarity-91,:condition,,,,,,,
260,1,930,To do otherwise would be dishonest.,[],DiGraph with 4 nodes and 3 edges,something,else,:mod,,,,,,,
261,1,933,polonium-210,[],DiGraph with 3 nodes and 2 edges,polonium,molecular-mass,:mod,,,,,,,
262,1,934,"As of 18 February 2017, the quantity of Iran's uranium enriched up to 3.67 percent  U-235 was 101.7 kg.","[{'LOC': 'Iran'}, {'MISC': 'U'}]",DiGraph with 22 nodes and 21 edges,uranium,molecular-mass,:mod,,,,,,,
265,1,952,"For once, she did not complain about the gift.",[{'PER': 'she'}],DiGraph with 4 nodes and 3 edges,complain-01 :polarity -,for-once,:mod,,,,,,,
266,1,954,This machine can perform several tasks at once.,[],DiGraph with 7 nodes and 6 edges,perform-02,at-once-02,:mod,,,,,,,
267,1,954,This machine can perform several tasks at once.,[],DiGraph with 7 nodes and 6 edges,machine,this,:mod,,,,,,,
268,1,955,We need to solve this problem once and for all.,[{'PER': 'We'}],DiGraph with 6 nodes and 5 edges,solve-01,once-and-for-all,:mod,,,,,,,
269,1,955,We need to solve this problem once and for all.,[{'PER': 'We'}],DiGraph with 6 nodes and 5 edges,problem,this,:mod,,,,,,,
272,1,958,"Once again, Russia vetoed the resolution.",[{'LOC': 'Russia'}],DiGraph with 8 nodes and 7 edges,veto-01,again,:mod,,,,,,,
273,1,958,"Once again, Russia vetoed the resolution.",[{'LOC': 'Russia'}],DiGraph with 8 nodes and 7 edges,again,once,:mod,,,,,,,
274,1,960,"2 Corinthians 1:1a,15-24 (NRSV)",[{'ORG': 'Corinthians'}],DiGraph with 17 nodes and 16 edges,verse,and,:mod,,,,,,,
275,1,960,"2 Corinthians 1:1a,15-24 (NRSV)",[{'ORG': 'Corinthians'}],DiGraph with 17 nodes and 16 edges,chapter,1,:mod,,,,,,,
279,1,967,ERK phosphorylates B-Raf on the S151 site.,"[{'ORG': 'ERK'}, {'MISC': 'B'}, {'MISC': 'Ra'}, {'MISC': 'S'}]",DiGraph with 14 nodes and 13 edges,amino-acid,151,:mod,,,,,,,
